所以现在你们所有人的好消息是我们对核心的
So the good news for all of you right now,
is that we're pretty much done with core
Docker 功能，所以在此时，我想说的是
Docker functionality, so at this point,
you're pretty much I would say like
Docker 的中间用户，我认为是非常酷的。
intermediate users of Docker,
which is pretty cool, I think.
我们会有更多样的生态系统
We are gonna get into some more kind of
ecosystem type things, so the first thing
我要讲的是像我们讲的多集装箱项目
I am going to talk about was like multi
container projects which we talked about
以及如何将类似容器连接到此容器。
in networking, and how to connect like
this container to this container.
但你能想象像另一个开发者一样
But can you imagine like trying
to get like another developer
在你的团队里做我们刚刚做的事吗
in your team to kinda do the exact
same thing that we just did?
就像一连串的九步，事情就会大错大错，
It would be like a series of like nine
steps and things would go wrong and
是个问题吧
be a problem, right?
如果我们能给它就好了，运行这个命令，
It would be better if we could just give
it like here, run this one command, and
它会把所有你需要的容器都装起来
it's gonna set up all
the containers that you need.
这就是 Docker Compose 会为我们做的事情，我们会在第二个方面谈论这个问题。
That's what Docker Compose is gonna do for
us and we'll talk about that in a second.
然后我们要进入库伯内特
And then we're gonna get into
Kubernetes which is, deserves
我们要去做最基本的 Kubernetes 的事情
three courses unto itself, so, we're going
to do the most basic Kubernetes thing so
你能理解它的存在和对你的一切
that you can understand what it is and
what it does for you.
然后我们就不去了你得去找
And then we're not gonna go any further
than that, you'll have to look for
其他的课程如果你真的想深入库伯内特的话
other courses if you really are interested
into getting deep into Kubernetes.
最后，我想介绍一些非 Docker 的技术，
Lastly, I wanted to introduce you to
some Non-Docker kind of technologies and
我们会和 Buildah 和 Podman 一起去的然后我们就会结束
we'll get there with Buildah and
Podman, and then we'll wrap up.
所以让我们继续进行 Docker
So let's go ahead and get into Docker
这实际上可能
compose, This actually might
是你们当中很多人在教室里走出去的最有用的东西之一。
be one of the most useful things that many
of you will walk away with this classroom.
Docker 编写对于开发环境非常有用，
Docker compose is extremely useful for
development environments,
对于生产环境，则较少。
less so for production environments.
我们会有理由在这里说
And we'll get into reasons why here
in momentarily but suffice to say,
大多数项目有一个或两个服务器或者至少两个
most projects have one or
two servers or at least two,
两台正运行的服务器对吧
two plus servers running, right?
您有一个数据库，可能有两个服务正在运行或类似的情况。
You have a database, maybe have two
services running or something like that.
而这些都是 Docker 的集合，就像我们在网络上看到的东西一样，
And getting that all set up with Docker,
like we saw with the networking stuff,
这很可能只是很烦人
it's possible, it's just annoying.
Docker 组合允许您在此处显示此容器，此处是此容器，
Docker compose allows you to say here's
this container, here's this container,
这里就是这个容器它们是如何相互交流的
here's this container,
here's how they talk to each other,
现在把它们都转起来给我，然后用一个配置文件来做。
now spin them all up for me, and then
you do it with one configuration file.
然后你说 Docker 会组成，它会为你做所有这些事情。
And then you say docker compose up,
it'll do all that stuff for you.
那么 Docker 编写的文档上说，它适合
So, Docker compose says on its
documentation, it is suitable for
生产环境，如果您基本有一个主机运行所有
production environments, if you have
like basically one host running all of
你的容器大多数人都不知道
your containers, which for
the most part most people don't.
我们有多台主机运行不同的容器，对吗 ?
We have multiple host running
our different containers, right?
你不想被绑在一个主机上你想说这个
And you don't wanna be tied to one host,
you wanna be able to say scale this
在这个问题上扔一百个容器
horizontally for me, throw a hundred
containers at this problem and
你不能用 Docker Compose 来做到这一点
you can't do that with Docker Compose so
that's just something to keep in mind.
如果您有生产环境，其中您需要多个容器
If you have a production environment
where you have many containers you want
多个主机，您的解决方案将是 Kubernetes ，我们接下来就会进入。
multiple hosts, your solution will be
Kubernetes and we'll get into that next.
Docker 组成的最有用的方法之一是非常有用的
One of the most useful things as well for
Docker compose it's very useful and
持续集成，持续交付类型的情境。
continuous integration,
continuous delivery kind of situations.
你可以说，嘿， Azure 管道或者特拉维斯 CI 之类的，
You can say, hey, Azure pipelines or
Travis CI or something like that,
将所有这些不同的容器旋转，确保所有这些单元测试和
spin up all of these different containers,
make sure that all these unit tests and
集成测试通过，然后将其向下旋转。
integration tests pass,
and then spin it down.
Docker 的编写非常好让我们继续吧
Docker compose really good at that so
let's go ahead and get into it,
所以我们从我们和我们一样的网络项目中
so let's do it from our same
networking project that we had with us,
我要停止我的服务器如果它会响
I'm gonna stop my server here,
if it'll respond,
它可能不会让我们继续
it might not So let's just go ahead and
杀了它我现在要把我的所有容器都杀了
kill it, I'm gonna kill all of
my running containers right now,
所以我要说 Docker 杀了 db 和黑体红
so I'm gonna say docker kill db and
bold rhodes.
所以如果我看码头的话我现在一无所有了
So if I look at docker ps I have
nothing running right now, great.
我们要在这个项目里做些什么
And what we're gonna do inside of this
particular project is we're gonna create
网络内部的新文件，项目，对吧 ?
a new file inside of the networking,
Project, right?
所以我们要用同样的方法
So we're gonna use the same one, and
我们会打电话给这个码头的人
we're gonna call this docker-compose.yml,
我把这个漂亮的粉色的小叮当容器
And for me I get this nice little pink
little docker container all right,
所以你们很多人可能不熟悉 YAML 是什么，
so many of you may not be
familiar with what YAML is,
如果你不是，对你好，我羡慕你。
if you're not, good for you, I envy you.
我不是一个大型的 YAML 扇子，其他人发誓，爱它，
[LAUGH] I'm not a big YAML fan,
other people swear by it, love it,
我称之为 " JSON 的 Python " 。
it's kind of like,
I call it the Python of JSON.
把所有有明显白色空间的东西都给库兹
Cuz everything where there's
significant white space, and
我不喜欢重要的空格，这只是我个人的意见。
I don't like significant white space,
that's just a personal opinion I hold.
所以我们要去看看 YAML 到底是什么
So we're going to, and
we'll walk through what YAML is but
基本上就像 JSON 没有所有不同语录之类的
basically it's like JSON without all of
the different quotes and stuff like that.
所以我们将把这个 Docker 编写的文件整理成一个文件
So we're going to code together this
Docker compose file it's going to outline
各种不同的容器是怎么连接在一起的对吧
how everything connects to each other all
the various different containers, right?
所以说，这就是我所关心的各种不同的容器，
So it's going to say, here's all these
various different containers I care about,
他们是如何相互联系的
here's how they connect to each other.
所以首先要确认的是 Docker 的版本
So the first thing you have to identify
it to is what version of Docker
你要用的是什么
compose are you going to be using.
所以我们要用三，告诉我版二还可以
So we're going to be using three,
I'm told that version two is still fine
就像那种反直觉的
to use like it that's kind
of counter intuitive for
人们认为我应该用三，三是最新的，但是版本二，
people to think I should use three,
three is the latest one, but version two,
它仍然有效，而且实际上还保留了它的两个版本。
it still works as well and they actually
still maintain version two of it as well.
我没用，所以我不能告诉你什么是区别，但是
I don't use it, so I can't really
tell you what the difference is, but
它就在外面还在工作
it is out there and still works.
然后我们会说服务我们要把所有
And then here we're gonna say services,
we're going to identify all
Docker 组成的各种不同服务将转至
the various different services that
Docker compose is going to spin up for
我们都是不同的容器好吗
us, all the various different containers,
okay?
所以这就是我说的他们的重要的空格
So this is what I'm talking about
with their significant whitespace, so
我在这儿打了冒号就意味着我要给它
I hit colon here and
I'm just that means that I'm gonna give it
做了很多事情然后你就得在这里缩进
multiple things after this and
then you have to indented here,
如果你不去缩进 YAML 会觉得它是另一个顶级的东西
if you don't indented YAML is gonna
think it's another top level thing.
所以我们要做一个叫做 " 网络容器 " 的
So we're gonna make one
called the web container and
我们要做一个叫 db 容器的人
we're gonna make one
called The db container.
Web 容器将是我们刚刚引用的项目
The web container is going to be our
project that we just quoted together with
蒙戈 db
Mongodb.
所以我们要告诉它 Docker 文件在哪里
So, we're gonna tell it,
where it's docker file is and
在此处需要构建 Docker 组成文件所在的位置，
where it needs to build it which is
here where the docker compose file is,
您还可以在 Docker 文件所在的位置指定 ./Dockerfile 。
you could also say like ./Dockerfile you'd
be pointing to where the Docker file is.
但如果你把它装在同一目录里有一个 Docker 文件
But if you just put it means there's
a Docker file in the same directory as
此 Docker 组成文件。
this Docker compose file.
> > 它会自动查找的。
&gt;&gt; It's gonna automatically look for it.
>> 确切地说，你知道你关心的是什么港口，在这里，
&gt;&gt; Exactly and you tell what ports
that you care about, and here,
你可以把它像个子弹一样，对，有点像个标记。
you can give it like a bullet of list,
right, kinda like mark down.
所以我们要把这些港口的清单给它建个清单
So we're gonna give it a build to list of
what ports will be on and expose where,
我们说 3000:3000，这就是你怎么用 Docker 来运行的，对吧 ?
let's say 3000:3000, that's very much how
you would run that with Docker, right?
当它暴露在 3000 端口 3000 的时候。
When it exposed Port 3000 on 3000.
我们要去做卷
Here, we're gonna do volumes,
就像我们之前说的
just like we were talking about before,
如何把我们的代码连接到这个
of how to connect our code to this.
所以我们要做的第一件事就是
So the first thing that we're
gonna do on this one is we're
我们的代码是存在的 : 家庭/节点 / 代码。
gonna say our code exists
at .: home/node/code.
把我们的集装箱里的所有东西都暴露在我们的整个密码库里
So expose everything inside of our
container like our entire code base
就会把我们的代码装进去
inside at home node code, so this is
going to mount our code into there so
那我们就可以写代码了吧
that then we can keep writing code, right?
>> 在 Docker 文件中等于单词目录，
&gt;&gt; And that equals word
directory in a Docker file,
其中- >> 就像绑定安装，
where-
&gt;&gt; It's like a bind mount,
它是一种捆绑式的安装，实际上它是什么。
it's a bind mount, is actually what it is.
然后我们要告诉它 home/node/code/node_modules，
And then we're gonna tell it that
home/node/code/node_modules,
把它分开处理
treat that separately.
基本上我们说的是不要带你的模块，你需要的是
And basically what we're saying is don't
bring over the node_modules, cuz you need
把它安装在里面，然后你告诉它，它是有联系的。
to install it inside of there, and
then when you tell it, this is linked.
所以链接，链接到数据库，
So links, this is linked to db,
这意味着我知道这两个集装箱必须相互沟通
which means that I know these two
containers need to talk to each other.
另一个问题是，因为它知道首先是联系，它将首先启动数据库，
And the other thing is, because it knows
links first, it's gonna start db first,
因为如果您尝试启动 Web Service ，首先它将查找
because if you try and start the web
service first it's gonna look for
蒙哥 DB 找不到它会崩溃的对吧
MongoDB and not find it and
it's gonna crash, right?
所以说你看 db，我先启动数据库，等待
So it's gonna say, you depend on db,
I'm gonna start db first, wait for
从那开始
that to finish starting,
然后我就开始网络了一切都能从正确的顺序开始
then I'll start web so that everything
can start in the right order.
还有一件东西在他们提供的地方
And then one more thing
underneath links where they give
它的环境变量，即 MONGO_CONNECTION_，
it the environment variable of where
to go, which is MONGO_CONNECTION_,
STRING: mongodb://
Db :27 017。
Db:27 017.
现在你会为你的各种微型服务做这些
Now, you would go do this for
all your various micro services, or
前端服务或所有正在构建的不同容器
front end services or all the different
containers that you are building and
开始，为了分贝，更简单。
starting up, for dB,
it's much more simple.
我们看到了一个我们希望它运行的图像
We've seen a pointed at which
image that we want it to run,
我们要做的就是图像 : 3。
which for us is gonna be image: mongo:3.
这将会很聪明地把它从 Docker Hub上取下来
And that's gonna be smart enough
to go get that off a Docker Hub,
作为 RDB 容器开始运行，这是另一种深兔洞，
start running it as RDB containers, this
is another kind of deep rabbit hole of,
您可以做的事情， Docker - 撰写可以为您做一些事情。
things you can do, Docker-compose
can do quite a few things for you.
这是最基本的版本。
This is pretty much the most
basic version of that for this.
好吧我在哪儿
All right, so where am I?
我进了集装箱我要回去联网
I am in into the container, so
I'm gonna go back into networking,
我要说码头上的破折号很重要
and I'm gonna say docker-compose,
that dash is important up.
在我们做这件事之前还有一件事
So one more thing before we run this,
我在这里忘了一个主要的斜杠，所以需要 /home/node/code。
I forgot a leading slash here,
so you need /home/node/code.
那么点，就像这样重复一次，这里的点说
So dot and just to kind of run through
that again, the dot here says that
这将会把所有东西都纳入 Docker 的目录中
this is going to take everything in
the directory of the Docker compose,
你可以做我不知道的事
and you could have done I don't know,
the whole path which for
我就会一直这样对吗
me would have been it would
have been this right?
所以我可以把所有这些都复制到那里
So I could have copied all of that And
put that right there, I do
而不是建议这样做，因为很明显，这对你的电脑很特别。
not suggest doing that, because obviously
that's very specific to your computer.
您想说的是 Docker 组成的目录中的所有内容
What you wanna say is everything inside of
this directory where the Docker compose
文件是，在容器中的 /home/node/code 中安装该文件。
file is, mount that in
the container at /home/node/code.
我忘了这个
And I had forgotten this leading slash,
一定要把那个引领人带在那儿好吗
make sure you have that
leading slash there, okay?
然后我们会说 Docker
And here we're gonna say Docker compose up
这应该能让我们的整个环境工作。
And this should get our
entire environment working.
好了，你运行 Docker 编写，并且有一堆输出和
Okay, so you ran Docker compose up,
and you got a bunch of output and
你会注意到的第一件事就是这些 db_1
the first thing you'll notice
here is all these db_1.
那么， Docker 编写的好东西是您可以实际运行多个版本的
So, the nice thing about Docker compose is
you can actually run multiple versions of
同样的容器我也不会告诉你怎么和 Mongo cuz 一起去
the same container, I'm not gonna show you
how to do that with Mongo cuz then have to
担心分片和副本集以及主项和辅助卷。
worry about sharding and replica sets and
primaries and secondaries.
但是 db_1 意味着它意味着它是第一个不同类型的
But that's what the db_1 means it means
it's the first of those various different
容器正在运行，并且
containers running, and
如果它看起来熟悉的都是 MongoDB 的输出，对吧 ?
if it looks familiar to it's
all the MongoDB output, right?
你可以在这里看到它实际上接收到一个客户端连接
So you can see here at this point it
actually receives a client connection
从驾驶员 node.js 开始，第三点是第三点，
from driver node.js, and it's running
the three point three point five,
是我们安装的驱动器。
driver which is one that we installed.
它来自 Linux ，它是 Node JS V12 ，是对的，
It's from Linux and
it's Node JS version 12, which is right,
这就是我们所做的
that's the one that we've made.
然后你可以在下面的 web_1中看到
And then you can see down here at web_1,
这是我们写的服务器的输出。
this is the output of our
server that we wrote.
所以现在理论上我应该可以点击这个
So now in theory I should be
able to click on this and
打开这个链接，这看起来很熟悉吗 ?
open this link, And
this looks very familiar to right?
这是我们刚刚在网络上写的另一个应用
This is the other app that
we just wrote in networking,
所以如果我加进去然后再回来
so if I go add, and then come back here.
你注意到所有东西都在工作所以这些都是
You notice that everything is working,
so these are the logs coming
从我们的 Node JS 应用程序中的前一个网络章节中写入的内容。
from our Node JS application that we wrote
right in the previous networking chapter.
如果你能来这里
And if you would come over here and
就像 /ad 一切都一样对吧
do like /ad everything is working
the same expect it right?
就像在 3000 口工作一样
So like it's working on port 3000,
这是我们在 Docker 编写文件中告诉它执行的操作。
which is what we told it to do
in the Docker compose file.
如果我们来这里说这一点
And if we come over here and
say go to this,
你可以看到数 : 11 一切都一样
you can see count: 11 everything's
working the same way.
但不需要手动将所有内容连接到网络和
But instead of having to connect
everything manually to a network and
说，好吧，这个容器跟这个讲，它是在这个网络上做的，
say like, okay, this container talks to
this one, it does it on this network,
那你就不用再这样了
blah blah blah,
you don't have to do that anymore.
我们可以通过制作一个 Docker 的 post 文件来做到这一点
We can do that just by making a Docker
post file that says, this container does
这个这个容器是这样做的，这些都是联系在一起的。
this, this container does this, and
these ones are linked together.
然后 Docker 只为您自己处理所有网络业务。
And then Docker just handles all of
the networking business for you by itself.
我是个大粉丝如果你不知道
I'm a big fan, if you can't tell,
所有与 Docker 合作的人都组成了
everything's working
with docker compose up.
你刚刚跟你的同事分享了你的 Docker 文件
You just shared your docker
compose file with your co-workers,
和你的队友合作他们可以说 Docker 是自己组成的
with your teammates and they can just
say docker compose up themselves,
他们不一定要了解所有东西是怎么连接在一起的
they don't necessarily have to understand
how everything connects together.
他们不需要与 Docker 联网进行手动交互
They don't have to manually
interact with docker networking,
所有事情都是在幕后发生的
everything just kinda happens for
them behind the scenes.
只要你现在需要，需要知道如何设置它，然后你就完成了。
Just you now need, needs to know how
to set it up and then you're done.